

□ (201) 394-8730 | ■ matt@borlax.com | ♠ https://borlax.com | • github.com/borlax

# About

Skilled technologist with 8+ years experience in Linux Administration and Data Center Operations. Involved in the on-site design, implementation, and management of physical data center environments, as well as administration of VPS and storage environments. Experience in both remote and local administration of systems including virtualization, backups, version control, and monitoring.

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

### The Constant Company, LLC / Vultr, LLC

LEAD LINUX SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

August 2017 - Present

- Management of a team with 30+ members with 9 direct reports.
- Team lead providing a point of escalation and mentorship for junior administrators.
- · Management of VM orchestration and deployment for clients across over 10,000 servers in 25 global locations.
- Project Planning via Jira ranging from deployments to software upgrades/patching.
- · Documentation of processes, operations and troubleshooting of Linux servers using Bookstack and Confluence.
- Level 1 technical support for customer VPS instances, bare metal servers, and add on features
- · Level 2 technical support for deployment platform, including troubleshooting of critical hardware and software infrastrtucture.
- · Monitoring and management of infrastructure, including KVM hypervisors, CEPH backed storage, and internal services.
- · Coordination with service owners, vendors and data center staff related to infrastructure maintenance, repair and expansion.

# Global Trading Systems, LLC / Strike Technologies

New York New York

DATA CENTER ENGINEER

December 2015 - August 2017

- On site management and maintenance of trading environment in multiple datacenter locations.
- · Cage and cabinet monitoring, break/fix and new rollouts from physical work to operating system and platforms using Foreman and Puppet.
- · Collaborate with engineering and software teams during troubleshooting, new service turnup and DR exercises.
- Maintained documentation and standard operating procedures for execution of data center ops.
- Documented and managed rack elevations and spare hardware inventory.
- Coordinate remote datacenter work with remote hands in data centers across Europe and Asia.
- · Network maintenance including Arista and Cisco configurations, cross connect turn up/down, fiber port troubleshooting (light meter, cleaning)

**NASDAQ OMX** Carteret, N.J.

#### DATA CENTER TECHNICIAN

February 2013 - December 2015

- Provide data center support for both internal systems/network teams and external customers.
- Management of projects including major installations and environment buildouts
- Cross connect running and terminations from internal routers to customer cabs/cages
- Copper and Fiber testing and fiber cleaning for various intracabinet and intercabinet connections.
- Remote hands support provided in person as well as via phone, IM, and email.
- · Maintained DCIM inventory of all rack elevations and cross connects.
- Constant monitoring of all server and network hardware

# Skills

Linux (Debian, RedHat, Arch) / Virtualization (KVM/QEMU, Virtual Box) / Ansible / Icinga/Nagios / CEPH

LAMP and LEMP Stacks / BASH / Python / PHP

Dell / Supermicro / HP / Cisco / Arista / Cumulus

Customer Service / Interdepartmental coordination / overseeing team operations

# Education

#### **New Jersey Institute of Technology**

Newark, NJ

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

# References

Furnished upon request.